NATALIE WILLIAMS

ADMINISTRATIVE MANAGER Secret Clearance

CONTACT



202.341.7766



nswilliams10@gmail.com

EDUCATION

Diploma

Eastern Senior High School, Washington, D.C.

SKILLS

- Content Management
- Administrative Operations
- Information Flow
- Project Management
- Records Management
- Cost-Benefit Analysis
- Project Prioritization
- Microsoft Excel
- Time and Attendance
- Scheduling
- Government Travel Systems
- WebTA System

OUALIFICATION SUMMARY

Over 13 years of experience managing the execution of sizable projects, administrative operations and training new personnel. Extensive experience in government time and attendance systems, as well as government travel policies and procedures. Utilizes interpersonal skills to build cohesive relationships and teams that achieve common goals. Creative solution-seeker and resourceful lead, consistently evaluating how resources are used to enhance production and reduce process duplication and wasteful spending.

CAREER OVERVIEW

Administrative Specialist October 2015- Current Position Department of Justice, Office of Justice Programs, Washington, D.C.

Oversees administrative operations including managing the supply inventory, directing the flow of information for two executive managers and facilities management. Directs the issuance of permanent parking permits for over 300 personnel, according to established policy and parking availability. Utilizes Microsoft Excel to document parking pass receipt, expiration dates and parking violations on spreadsheets. Supports COOP Program by arranging trainings/seminars. Arranges the approval and reservations of domestic and foreign travel for eight senior principals using the E2 travel system. Utilizes card management skills to protect sensitive financial information. Processes reimbursement claims for each trip in accordance with regulations and policies. Prepares weekly and monthly employee status reports for the division. Reviews official correspondence for compliance, spelling and grammar errors.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS:

- Analyzes content on the office's SharePoint site. Creates visual advertisements, adding new material and deleting outdated material.
- Performed cost-benefit analysis to compare prices of various office equipment. As a result, the office's supply expenses decreased and new vendors were identified.
- Provided training on the standard operating procedures of the office to the Records Management Assistant.

Department of Commerce, Washington, D.C.

Managed the office's domestic and international travel schedule by arranging frequent travel accommodations for 30 senior management officials. Planned trip itineraries in accordance with administrative polices and time commitments. Researched travel destinations and provided pertinent information about the location such as currency exchange rates, time zones and State Department travel warnings. Upon their return, processed receipts and travel vouchers ensuring adherence to all travel regulations. Organized travel reservations and reimbursements, according to the department's records management policies. Reviewed official correspondence for compliance with organizational policy.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS:

- Trained two new hires on arranging travel using the E2 system.
- Recognized for my ability to arrange flights that maximized the travel budget by suggesting alternative routes and dates.

Program Analyst

April 2009 – March 2014

Department of Homeland Security, Immigration & Customs Enforcement, Washington, D.C.

Coordinated commercial travel arrangements in support of ICE's Enforcement Removal Operation's mission. Served as the final liaison with Embassies, Field Offices, ICE officers and ICE attaches globally ensuring safety and guidelines were met for escorting officers and illegal aliens. Tracked all removals on a Microsoft Excel spreadsheet that included travel information. Reviewed and analyzed various countries travel requirements/restrictions. Collaborated with ICE agents once travel reservations were finalized, and provided all relevant travel information to the agents. Protected all personal identifiable information (PII) by securing information in locked file cabinets and shredding sensitive documents.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS:

- Processed travel arrangements on a monthly average of 150 illegal alien removals while maintaining an error ratio below 1%.
- Based on my removal proceedings expertise, recommended to support the processing of urgent removals to aid the agency in meeting its deadlines. As a result, received the 2014 ICE Support Customer Service Award.

Communication Specialist

July 2007 – October 2008

U.S. Department of State, Passport Agency, Washington, D.C.

Verbally interpreted policies and requirements to an average of 250 callers and visitors each day. Contacted customers by phone for verification of mailing addresses and other information in response to telephone calls or e-mails received through the National Passport Information Center (NPIC) Generated Informational Response Letters (IRLs) to request additional information or documentation for adjudicated passport applications. Utilized the current TDIS-PD and PRISM computer operating system including the creation of document batches, document imaging and reviewing, retrieval of individual application information, data entry, book printing, sorting and affixing postage to sealed envelopes.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS:

- Processed over 300 Passport Books daily, surpassing agency requirements.
- Provided training to an average of 10 new hires on document editing, photo imaging review and passport information.